James Hester

1078 Wisdom Ct Glen Burnie, MD 21061

641.451.1155 himself@jameshesterjr.com

Summary

As an innovative critical thinker, candid communicator, enthusiastic engineer, and driven technologist, I am looking to contribute to the rapidly evolving approach and applications of technology on related business frontiers. With over 15 years of professional experience, diverse technical range, and an unflinching passion for development and growth, I am seeking to fulfill a leadership role that encourages individual success along side team efforts and empowers contributors to actualize bold ambitions.

Experience

Owner / Consultant

Abaci Tech LLC, Baltimore, MD - 2017-Current

- Own and operate private Corp offering technology services.
- Service various contracts for consulting, architecture, development, implementation, and other technology related duties, as needed.
- Introduce and train aspiring technologists relevant skills and principles.

Senior Lead Software Engineer

Chronicle of Higher Education, Washington, DC – 2016-2017

- Lead development team to build systems for support and customer products.
- Implemented TDD and BDD practices to refine development process.
- Orchestrated business domain model, abstracting and clarifying long term costly dependencies.

Senior Full Stack Developer

Jellyfish Marketing, Baltimore, MD – 2015

- Acted as principal technical representative and engineer for United States offices.
- Introduced Agile principles to daily work processes.
- Researched and promoted upcoming technologies.
- Built and consulted for both client facing proposals and internal projects.

Technical Operations Lead

Hashtag LLC, Denver, CO - 2013-2015

- Managed ongoing technical operations.
- Investigated and developed business support software.
- Architected business domain for manufacturing, communications, customer relations, sales and marketing, among other technological supported duties.

Chief Technical Lead

Think LLC, Fairfield, IA - 2010-2013

- Researched and identified business and technical requirements of client needs.
- Coordinated client and team members for contract and project organization.
- Reviewed code and products to endorse outstanding standards of technical quality.
- Communicated technological, operational, and cultural company direction.

Experience (Continued)

Miscellaneous Independent Contractor & Consultant

Ebay, Samsung, Lego, Etc. - 2003-2018

Various contracts offering exploration and application of multiple roles, teams, skillsets, and

duties.

Education

Computer Science & Mathematics

Maharishi University of Management, Fairfield, IA 2009-2011

74 Credit Hours Completed

Technologies

Following is a cursory list of recent or salient technologies I utilize and maintain varying levels of expertise with.

Techniques & Philosophies

Agile, Behavior Driven Design, Test Driven Design, REST, Microservices, Service Oriented Architecture, Software Craftsmanship, Clean Code. MV* Architecture, Hexagonal Architecture, Radical Candor, Object Oriented Programming / Protocol Oriented Programming, Functional Reactive Programming

Tools, Platforms, & Frameworks

Git, Composer, PHPUnit, Behat, Jenkins, Chef, Swagger (Open API Specification), Webpack, Babel, Axios, XCTest, Quick/Nimble, Swagger, Postman, Kubernetes, Amazon Web Services, Node.js, Adobe Creative Cloud, Laravel, Symfony, Vue, React, Angular, JQuery, Bootstrap 4.0, MySQL, Django, Flask, Oracle DB, NoSQL

Languages

PHP, Swift, Javascript, Python, Java, C/C++, Haskell, HTML/CSS

Updated 5/24/2018